# **Rudra Dutt**

✓ dutt\_rudra@outlook.com (+91) 84099-44662 in linkedin.com/in/rudradutt/

#### **Overview**

Business Intelligence and Cloud Data Warehousing professional with over three years of experience. Delivered projects with 100% completion, over ~93% of which were on time, and less than ~5% needed rework. Demonstrated experience in Business and Functional requirement gathering. Have worked with several business intelligence technologies including Power BI, Tableau, and Qlik. Incredibly flexible with culture, with a willingness to learn new technologies and thrive in a high-powered environment.

#### Skills

SQL | Power BI | Tableau | Data Mining | MS Excel | MS Powerpoint | AWS Athena Azure Data Lake | Python | ETL Tools | Data Visualization | Data Analysis | AWS Glue

# **Professional Experience**

03/2020 - present

## **Business Intelligence Analyst, Innovation Junction LLC**

- Developing new logical reports and participating in automation projects using BI tools and cloud technologies. Creating ad-hoc analysis according to the requirements of stakeholders.
- Using multiple data analysis, ETL, and BI tools to provide daily, weekly and monthly analysis related to monitoring: Sales Analysis, Customer Rationalization, Product Profitability, Financial reports, and Inventory monitoring reports.
- Created an application that helped in reducing the variance of forecast to 2%
- Creation and monitoring of targets, KPIs, and forecasts on a monthly basis
- Responsible for delivery and maintenance of standard quality reports for engaged business partners on key metrics and performance measures
- Recommend actions by analyzing and interpreting data and making comparative analyses; study proposed changes in methods and materials

06/2019 - 02/2020

## **Equity Analyst,** Karvy Stock Broking Ltd

- Utilized strong decision-making and technical knowledge to cater to clients who needed buy/sell recommendations in the stock market
- Worked to build long-term relationships with clients by problem-solving around their pain points
- Managed client's portfolio of stocks in order to maximize profit
- Worked to support the company mission and adhere to company protocol at all times
- Worked with cross-functional teams to structure problems, identify appropriate data sources, extract data and utilize them for solving business problems

### **Education**

2017 – 2019 Ranchi **Masters in Business Administration,** Central University of Jharkhand

Major in Marketing

### **Certifications**

- The complete SQL Bootcamp
- Python for Data Analysis and Visualization ☐
- Scientific Computing with Python ☑